LEONARDO SALAZAR CENICEROS

+52 (871) 138-0986 · AGE 22 · TORREÓN, COAHUILA, MÉXICO · LEOSALAZAR97@GMAIL.COM

About me

Dedicated and passionate, interested in computer science from a very young age and 6 years of working experience. Able to develop in multiple areas, great versatility and expertise in several scopes, such as web development, teaching and customer services.

Social and logical abilities that help for troubleshooting, always ready to learn something new and willing to sort out adversities even under a lot of pressure. All of this adds up to being a role model, always delivering the best and encouraging everyone to do the same.

LANGUAGES

English Fluent

French Intermediate



PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS



















EDUCATION

COLEGIO CERVANTES DE TORREÓN - HIGH SCHOOL

Graduated with a final score of 9.1 / 10

August 2012 - May 2015

<u>INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE LA LAGUNA</u> - BACHELOR DEGREE OF COMPUTER SCIENCE Current score of **9.0 / 10**

August 2015 - Will Finish on June 2021

EXPERIENCE

VR & AR ENGINEER

+52 (871) 400-1410 - LUIS ROBERTO HERNÁNDEZ - FREE LANCER FOR PEÑOLES

Creating more interactive content for one of the most important museums in Torreón, Coahuila. Promoting the use of new technologies such as VR & AR for delivering great experiences as you learn having fun.

January 2019 - September 2020

WEB DEVELOPER

+52 (871) 462-4931 - ALDO SANDOVAL - INTARSIA

Angular and .NET development for a school management system, creating APIs and WebServices that connects to an SQLDatabase. Testing and improving every component in the system delivering great performance.

September 2019 - December 2019

ROBOTICS MENTOR

+52 (871) 158-2039 - MAX CUEVAS - FGC NATIONAL SELECTION

In charge of a group of 5 high school students who are the mexican selection for an international competition held in Dubai, helping them with programming manners as well as consolidating an effective team work.

June 2019 - October 2019

ROBOTICS COACH

+52 (871) 158-2039 - MAX CUEVAS - FTC TEAM CERBOTICS 15600

Coach of a rookie team formed by 15 9th graders which won the Control Award and National Winner Award, recognized for being outstanding in automatization manners for a competing robot and achieving the Championship Pass.

September 2018 - May 2019

LEGO COACH

+52 (871) 158-2039 - MAX CUEVAS - FLL TEAM CERBOTICS LEGO

Mentor of a small amount of kids, all of them with ages from 12 to 14. Teaching them how to make investigations and to be assertive on the resolution of problems.

September 2018 - May 2019

ROBOTICS MENTOR

+52 (871) 158-2039 - MAX CUEVAS - FRC TEAM CERBOTICS 4400

Teaching classes of basic programming with LabView and Java for the control and automatization of mechanisms for the Chairman's Award Winner team in the FIRST Robotics Competition. With the duty to teach all the learning lived as a founder member of the team in 2012. Participated in the Championship for 3 consecutive years since 2017. January 2017 - May 2019

VIDEOGAME DEVELOPER

+52 (871) 304-8802 - DANIEL SEIJAS - CURIOSITY EDUCACIÓN

Engineering educational videogames for a web platform using only HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript, guaranteeing the best performance online as the developed games use very little resources. July 2016 - December 2016

WEB DEVELOPER

+52 (871) 104-2711 - LUIS PADRÓN - COMPAX

In charge of the development of entertaining apps for a web platform using Javascript, HTML5 and CSS3 through the second semester of 2015. In charge of the management and development of an administrative system for the teachers and financial manners of a school. Also developed a Java Desktop Application for generating dynamic web pages. July 2015 - December 2015

WEB DESIGNER

+52 (871) 264-6270 - FELIPE RAMOS - CAD HOUSE

Designed a web site using Adobe Muse planning the structure of the page being ready to escalate and easy to use for the client and adminitrator, as well as defining the site identity and colors.

June 2014 - August 2014

WEB DEVELOPER

+52 (871) 104-2711 - LUIS PADRÓN - COMPAX

Developed a live chat for a web site and used jQuery and CSS for styling and animating the content of an educational platform which was used by the SEP (Secretaría de Educación Pública) on Yucatán.

June 2013 - August 2013

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Participated in the OMI (Olimpiada Mexicana de Informática) for 4 consecutive years, achieving Bronze, Silver and Gold Medals in Regionals and one Bronze Medal in the National of 2014.
- Medal "Bulmaro Valdez Anaya" to Distinguished Citizenship in Science and Technology of Torreón in 2018 for inspiring the community through social outreach and STEM promoting activities.



Team Founder 2012



1st Place Science Fair



OMI Medals (2012-2014)



OMI National Bronze



FLL Medals



FTC Winning Medal



Chairman's Award Medal



Medal Bulmaro Valdez Anaya



FGC Certificate of Excellence

REFERENCES

- +52 (871) 158-2039 · Max Cuevas · Colegio Cervantes Jr High School Principle
- +52 (871) 462-4931 · Aldo Sandoval · Intarsia
- +52 (871) 266-0836 · Ricardo de Ávila · College Professor